You can't outrun your destiny.
Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings is a action, adventure,
fantasy film directed by Destin Daniel Cretton.
Shang-Chi must confront the past he thought he left behind when he is
drawn into the web of the mysterious Ten Rings organization.
Shaun / Shang-Chi, played by Simu Liu.
Xu Wenwu, played by Tony Leung Chiu-wai.
Katy, played by Awkwafina.
Trevor Slattery, played by Ben Kingsley.
Xialing, played by Meng'er Zhang.
Li, played by Fala Chen.
Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings is a 2021 American superhero film
based on Marvel Comics featuring the character Shang-Chi.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion
Pictures, it is the 25th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Destin Daniel Cretton from a screenplay he wrote with Dave Callaham and Andrew Lanham, and stars Simu Liu as Shang-Chi
alongside Awkwafina, Meng'er Zhang, Fala Chen, Florian Munteanu, Benedict Wong, Yuen Wah, Michelle Yeoh, Ben Kingsley, and Tony Leung.
In the film, Shang-Chi is forced to confront his past when his father Wenwu (Leung), the leader of the Ten Rings
terrorist organization, draws Shang-Chi and his sister Xialing (Zhang) into a search for a mythical village.
A film based on Shang-Chi entered development in 2001, but work did not
begin in earnest until December 2018 when Callaham was hired.
Cretton joined in March 2019 and the film's title and
primary cast were announced that July.
This revealed the film's connection to the Ten Rings organization, which previously appeared throughout the MCU, and
its leader Wenwu who was adapted from the problematic comic book characters Fu Manchu and the Mandarin.
Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings is the first Marvel Studios
film with an Asian director and a predominantly Asian cast.
Filming began in Sydney in February 2020 but was put on
hold in March due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
Production resumed in August and ended in October, with
additional filming in San Francisco.
Brad Allan and other members of the Jackie Chan Stunt
Team coordinated the fight sequences.
Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings premiered in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on August 16, 2021,
and was released in the United States on September 3 as part of Phase Four of the MCU.
It grossed over $432 million worldwide, making it the
ninth-highest-grossing film of 2021.
It set several box office records and received positive reviews from critics, many of whom praised the exploration and representation of
Asian culture which differentiated the film from the rest of the MCU, as well as the action sequences and Leung's performance.
The film received various accolades, including a nomination for
Best Visual Effects at the 94th Academy Awards.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of martial arts, superhero, based on
comic, mixed martial arts (mma), east asian lead.